Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Writings
  - Subseries: IV.4: Manuscripts, 1930s-2002
    - "On Freud's forgetting of 'Signorelli'"
      - Annotated typescripts, outlines, research notes, and correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 1)
      - Research file and notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 2)
      - Research file, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 3)
    - "Wolvinius Magister Phaber: the crowning of an artist in the early Middle Ages"
      (Composed of three organized parts and largely paginated, this manuscript includes a large portion of footnotes that Schapiro meticulously compiled. In an annotation to the title statement of the manuscript found in file 4, Box 261, the original term used for "crowning" is "consecration." The annotated title is used for clarity. Consult file 14, Box 261 for Schapiro's section titles and general outline of the manuscript. Schapiro would generally interleave his research notes into the files with paginated manuscripts)
      - Part I: pages 1-12 -- Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 4)
      - Part I: pages 13-26 -- Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 5)
      - Part I: pages 27-39 -- Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 6)
      - Part I: edited versions -- Annotated typescripts and editorial notes, 1980-1990s (Box 261, Folder 7)
        (Edits and notes are largely by Judy Sund and completed in 1983. Lillian Milgram Schapiro's editorial notes are also included)
      - Part I: editorial file -- 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 8)
        (Photocopy of assembled typescripts and research notes compiled by Lillian Milgram Schapiro)
      - Part II -- Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 9)
      - Part II: edited drafts, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 10)
        (Drafts edited by Robert Melzak and include three versions: Schapiro's original; the edited version; and a transcription of an unknown recording. Accompanied by correspondence and computer disk carrying electronic files)
      - Part III -- Research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 11)
      - Early drafts and research notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Outlines, 1980s-1990s (Box 261, Folder 14)
      - Footnote indexes, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 1)
      - Footnotes 1-10 -- Annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 2)
      - Footnotes 1-37 -- Early drafts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 3)
      - Footnotes 1-44 -- Annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 4)
      - Footnotes 11-20 -- Printouts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 5)
      - Footnotes 21-37 -- Printouts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 6)
      - Footnotes 34-37 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 7)
      - Footnotes, 38-58 --Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 8)
      - Footnotes 59-79 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 9)
      - Footnotes 73-80 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 262, Folder 10)
      - Footnotes 81-91 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 1)
      - Footnotes 92-100 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 2)
      - Footnotes 101-108 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990 (Box 263, Folder 3)
      - Footnotes 109-118 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 4)
      - Footnotes 123-130 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 5)
      - Footnotes 131-142 -- Printouts and annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 6)
      - Footnotes: Part I -- Annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 7)
      - Complete footnotes -- Annotated typescripts, 1980s-1990s (Box 263, Folder 8)
      - Complete footnotes -- Printout, 1990s (Box 263, Folder 9)
        (Created by Robin Sand following Schapiro's complete footnotes found in file 8, Box 263)
      - Reproductions and lists, 1980s-1990s (Box 264, Folder 1)
      - Research files, 1980s-1990s, (2 Folders) (Box 264, Folder 2 to 3)
    - "Selected essays in the history of art: Hebrew edition" -- Correspondence and editorial notes, 1993-2003 (Box 264, Folder 4)
      (This publication was to be edited by Mordechai Omer and published by the Tel Aviv University of Art Gallery and Old Jaffa Press. Omer began working with Schapiro in 1993 to formulate a list of works to be translated and published, but that was never realized. Lillian Milgram Schapiro began working on this project in 2003 but a published work never materialized. Title was derived from editorial notes found in the file)
    - "Burial at Ornans"
      (Referring to the painting by Gustave Courbet, this manuscript survives primarily as printouts created using Schapiro's research notes and outlines from the 1940s-1960 found in files 5 and 6 in Box 264. Similar elements and motifs in this manuscript can be found in Shapiro's published article "Courbet and popular imagery: an essay on realism and naïveté" published in the Warburg Journal. In the 1990s Lillian Milgram Schapiro circulated Schapiro's research material on Courbet to Maura Reilly and Robin Sand to reconstruct the text into manuscript form. As a result, files for this manuscript have printout versions interleaved with Lillian Milgram Schapiro's editorial notes and Schapiro's photocopied notes in a semi-paginated format. When possible, pagination was supplied using annotations provided)
      - Research notes, outlines, and clippings, 1940s-1960s (Box 264, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Pages 1-10 -- Printouts, editorial notes, and research notes, 1996-1996 (Box 264, Folder 7)
      - Page 4a -- Printouts, editorial notes, and research notes, 1996-1997 (Box 264, Folder 8)
      - Pages 11-14 -- Printouts, editorial notes, and research notes, 1996-1997 (Box 265, Folder 1)
      - Corrected draft -- Printouts and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 265, Folder 2)
      - Edited draft -- Printouts and correspondence, 2002 (Box 265, Folder 3)
        (Edited draft was created by Robin Sand and correspondence in this file details her edits in comparison to the published Courbet essay)
      - Edited draft -- Printouts and correspondence, 2002 (Box 265, Folder 4)
        (Edited draft was created by Maura Reilly and accompanied by correspondence relating to comparisons with the published Courbet essay)
      - Editorial notes, 1996-1997 (Box 265, Folder 5)
        (Notes are by Lillian Milgram Schapiro)
      - Research files, 1980s-1990s, (2 Folders) (Box 265, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Reproductions and research notes, 1960s-1980s (Box 265, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 265, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: IV.5: Publications, 1928-2009
    Subseries IV.5 contains material relating to all of Schapiro's work that were published either in his lifetime or posthumously. This includes material from all of his "Selected Writings" series published by George Braziller, Inc. a s well as books that were published posthumously and edited and compiled by Lillian Milgram Schapiro.
    For articles and reviews that were reprinted in Schapiro's "Selected Writings" series, consult Subseries: IV.2: Articles and Subseries: IV.6: Reviews where they are filed.
    While the bulk of the material dates after 1950, the earliest record in this subseries is Art in the contemporary world a 1928 reprint of An introduction to contemporary civilization in the west: a syllabus.
    - Art in the contemporary world ( 928; reprint of An introduction to contemporary civilization in the west: a syllabus. New York: Columbia University Press). -- Photocopies (Box 266, Folder 1)
    - Vincent van Gogh. New York: Harry N. Abrams, 1950 and reprints
      - Introduction and individual art works -- Annotated typescripts, 1940s-1950, (3 Folders) (Box 266, Folder 2 to 4)
      - Introduction and research notes -- Annotated typescripts, 1940s-1950 (Box 266, Folder 5)
        (Includes notes and studies that were not published in the 1950 publication)
      - Preface -- Annotated typescripts, 1940s-1950 (Box 266, Folder 6)
      - Research notes, 1940s-1950 (Box 266, Folder 7)
        (Includes notes and studies on St. Remy and Auvers that were not published)
      - Research notes, 1940s-1950 (2 Folders (Box 266, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Correspondence and reviews, 1951-1973 (Box 266, Folder 10)
      - Reviews, 1950s (Box 266, Folder 11)
        (Reviews in German)
      - Correspondence, 1950s-1980s (Box 266, Folder 12)
    - Paul Cézanne. New York: Harry N. Abrams. 1952 and reprints.
      - Pages 1-108 -- Annotated typescripts, 1940s-1952 (Box 266, Folder 14)
      - Introduction, acknowledgements, and reproductions list -- Annotated typescripts, 1940s-1952 (Box 267, Folder 1)
      - German translation -- Annotated typescript, 1956 (Box 267, Folder 2)
        (Published in Cologne, Germany by M. Dumont Schauberg)
      - Drafts and research notes, 1940s-1952, (7 Folders) (Box 267, Folder 3 to 9)
      - Proofs, 1952 (Box 267, Folder 10)
    - The Parma Ildefonsus: a Romanesque illuminated manuscript from Cluny, and Related Works. New York: College Art Association of America, 1964
      - Annotated book, 1964 (Box 267, Folder 11)
      - Research notes, 1950s-1964 (Box 267, Folder 12)
        (Notes chiefly on text, history, and styles)
      - Research notes, 1950s-1964 (Box 267, Folder 13)
        (Notes chiefly on ornament and history of the manuscript)
        - Research notes, 1950s-1964 (Box 267, Folder 14)
          (Notes chiefly relating to Cluny and Burgundinian manuscripts)
        - Research notes, 1950s-1964 (Box 267, Folder 15)
          (Notes chiefly on Limoges manuscript of Ildefonsus from the Bibliothèque nationale de France)
          - Research notes and drafts, 1950s-1964, (5 Folders) (Box 268, Folder 1 to 5)
          - Research notes and correspondence, 1950s-1964, (3 Folders) (Box 268, Folder 6 to 8)
          - Manuscripts cited -- Index, 1964 (Box 268, Folder 9)
          - Reviews, 1964 (Box 268, Folder 10)
      - Words and pictures: on the literal and the symbolic in the illustration of a text. Approaches to Semiotics series 11, ed. Thomas A. Sebeok. The Hague and Paris: Mouton, 1973.
        - Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1960s-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 269, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Drafts and research notes, 1960s-1973 (Box 269, Folder 3)
        - Research notes, 1960s-1973, (3 folders) (Box 269, Folder 4 to 6)
          - Editorial notes, 1960s-1973 (Box 269, Folder 7)
          - Reproductions lists, 1960s-1973 (Box 269, Folder 8)
          - Correspondence, reproductions, and clippings, 1970s-1980s (Box 269, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence, 1960s-1970s (Box 269, Folder 10)
          (Accompanied by review of the Italian translation)
          - Correspondence, 1970-1996 (Box 269, Folder 11)
      - Selected Papers I: Romanesque Art. New York: George Braziller, 1977.
        - Annotated book, 1977 (Box 270, Folder 1)
        - Preface -- Research notes, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 2)
        - "From Mozarbic to Romanesque in Silos"
          - Reproductions, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 3)
          - Reproductions, 1977 (Box 633, Folder 8)
        - "The sculpture of Souillac" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 4)
        - "On geometrical schematism in Romanesque art" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 5)
        - "A relief in Rodez and the beginnings of Romanesque sculpture in southern France" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 6)
        - "Two Romanesque drawings in Auxerre and some iconographic problems" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 270, Folder 7)
        - Footnotes, 1976 (Box 270, Folder 8)
          (Chiefly footnote number 66 of Moissac essay. Accompanied by research notes and correspondence)
        - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1970s, (4 Folders) (Box 270, Folder 9 to 12)
        - Reviews, 1977 (Box 270, Folder 13)
    - Selected Papers II: Modern Art: 19th and 20th Centuries. New York: George Braziller, 1978 1982.
      - Annotated book, 1978 (Box 271, Folder 1)
      - Prefatory note -- Annotated typescript, 1978 (Box 271, Folder 2)
      - "The apples of Cézanne: an essay on the meaning of still-life" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 3)
      - "Courbet and popular imagery" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 4)
      - "On a painting of van Gogh" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 5)
      - "Seurat" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 6)
      - "Picasso's Woman with a fan" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 7)
      - "Chagall's Illustration for the Bible" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 8)
      - "Introduction of modern art in America: the armory show" -- Reproductions,1 970s (Box 271, Folder 9)
      - "Arshile Gorky" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 10)
      - "The nature of abstract art" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 11)
      - "Recent abstract art" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 12)
    - "Mondrian: order and randomness in painting"
      (While Schapiro worked on this essay for several years, it was first published in this volume)
    - Annotated typescript, 1960s-1970s (Box 271, Folder 13)
    - Research notes and drafts, 1960s-1970s (Box 271, Folder 14)
    - Research ntoes, 1960s-1970s (Box 271, Folder 15)
    - Reproductions, 1978 (Box 271, Folder 16)
    - Footnotes, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 17)
    - Unpublished Matisse essay -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 271, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1970s, (3 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Reviews, 1978, (2 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Selected Papers Ill: Late Antique, Early Christian, and Medieval Art New York: George Braziller, 1979.
      - "A note on the Mérode altarpiece" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 6)
      - "Ancient mosaics in Israel: late antique art: pagan, Jewish, Christian" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 7)
      - "The Joseph scenes on the Maximianus throne in Ravenna" -- Reprductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 8)
      - "The place of the Joshua Roll in Byzantine history" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 9)
      - "The frescoes of Castelseprio"
        - Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 10)
        - Reproductions, 1979 (Box 633, Folder 9)
      - "Notes on Castelseprio" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 11)
      - "The Carolingian copy of the Calendar of 354" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 12)
      - "The religious meaning of the Ruthwell Cross" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 13)
      - "The bomwan and the bird on the Ruhwell Cross and other works" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 14)
      - "Marginal images and drôlerie" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 15)
      - "The decoration of the Leningrad manuscript of Bede" -- Reproductions, 1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 272, Folder 16 to 17)
      - "A note on the wall strips of Saxon churches" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 18)
      - "'Cains jaw-bone that did the first murder" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 19)
      - "The image of the disappearing Christ" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 272, Folder 20)
      - "The angel and the ram in Abraham's sacrifice" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 1)
      - "The Beatus Apocalypse of Gerona" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 2)
      - "An illuminated English psalter of the early thirteenth century" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 3)
      - "On an Italian painting of the flagellation of Christ in the Frick collection" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 4)
      - "The Bird's Head Haggada, an illustrated Hebrew Manuascript circa 1300" -- Reproductions, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1970s (Box 273, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Reviews, 1979 (Box 273, Folder 8)
      - Corrections and editorial notes, 1977-1979 (Box 273, Folder 9)
        (Includes material from the first two volumes of Schapiro's selected works)
      - Arte romanica. Translated by Adriano Sofri. Turin: Giulio Einaudi, 1982. -- Reviews, 1982 (Box 273, Folder 10)
        (Italian translation of Selected Papers I: Romanesque Art)
      - Style, Artiste et Société. Translated by Blaise Allan et. al. Paris: Editions Gallimard, 1982.
        - "Sur quelques problèmes de sémiotique de l'art visual: champ et véhicule dans les signes iconiques" -- Annotated typescript, 1970s-1980s (Box 273, Folder 11)
        - Editorial notes, 1970s-1980s, (4 Folders) (Box 273, Folder 12 to 15)
        - Editorial notes and correspondence, 1970s-1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 273, Folder 16 to 17)
        - Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 274, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1981-1999 (Box 274, Folder 2)
        - Reviews, 1982 (Box 274, Folder 3)
      - Moderne kunst: 19. und 20. jahrhundert ausgewählte aufsätze. Cologne: DuMont Buchverlag, 1982 -- Reviews, 1982 (Box 274, Folder 4)
        (German translation of Selected Papers II: Modern Art: 19th and 20th Centuries)
      - Estudios sobre el Románico. Translated by Maria Luisa Balseiro Madrid: Alianza Editorial, 1984 -- Reviews, 1984 (Box 274, Folder 5)
        (Spanish translation of Selected Papers I: Romanesque Art)
      - The Romanesque sculpture of Moissac. New York: George Braziller, 1985
        (Reprint of Schapiro's dissertation which was originally published in Art Bulletin. This reprint includes photographs by David Finn)
        - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1985 (Box 274, Folder 6)
        - Reviews, 1985 (Box 274, Folder 7)
        - L'arte moderna translated by Renato Pedio. Turin: Giuliu Einaudi Editore, no date. -- Reviews, 1986 (Box 274, Folder 8)
          (Italian translation of Selected Papers II: Modern Art: 19th and 20th Centuries
      - Selected papers IV: theory and philosophy of art: style, artist, and society. New York: George Brazillcr. 1994
        - Preface -- Annotated typescripts and notes, 1990s (Box 274, Folder 9)
        - "Further notes on Heidegger and van Gogh"
          (Previously unpublished essay published for the first time in this volume)
          - Annotated typescripts, 1990s, (2 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 10 to 11)
          - Annotated typescript and research notes, 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 12 to 13)
          - Correspondence, 1981-1994 (Box 274, Folder 14)
          - Research notes, 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 274, Folder 15 to 16)
          - Research file, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 1)
        - "Further notes on Freud and Leonardo"
          - Research notes, 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 2 to 3)
        - "On some problems in the semiotics of visual art: field and vehicle in image-signs" -- Reproductions, 1990s (Box 275, Folder 4)
        - "On perfection, coherence, and unity of form and content" -- Reproductions, 1990s (Box 275, Folder 5)
        - "Style" -- Reproductions, 1990s (Box 275, Folder 6)
        - "Eugène Fromentin as critic" -- Reproductions, 1990s (Box 275, Folder 7)
        - "Still life as a personal object: a note on Heidegger and Van Gogh" -- Reproductions, 1990s (Box 275, Folder 8)
        - Reproductions lists, 1990s, (2 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Corrections and editorial notes, 1977-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 275, Folder 11 to 13)
          (Includes material relating to Schapiro's other collected volumes)
        - Contract, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 14)
        - Book jacket illustration proof, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 15)
        - Reviews, 1994 (Box 275, Folder 16)
      - Oxford art journal 17, no. 1 (1994): 3-104
        (Special issue on Meyer Schapiro)
        - Notes and table of contents, 1994 (Box 276, Folder 1)
        - "A Vermont visit with Meyer Schapiro (August 1991)" -- Transcript and correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 276, Folder 2)
        - Reproductions, 1994 (Box 276, Folder 3)
      - Word, script, and pictures: the semiotics of visual language. New York: George Braziller, 1996
        - Reproductions, 1996, (5 Folders) (Box 276, Folder 4 to 8)
        - Reviews, 1996 (Box 276, Folder 9)
      - Impressionism: reflections and perceptions. New York: George Braziller, 1997
        - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 276, Folder 10)
        - Reproductions, 1997 (Box 276, Folder 11)
        - Reproductions, 1997 (Box 277, Folder 1)
        - Reviews, 1997 (Box 277, Folder 2)
      - A kind of rapture / Robert Bergman; introduction by Toni Morrison; afterword by Meyer Schapiro. New York: Pantheon Books, 1998 -- Printouts, 1998 (Box 277, Folder 3)
        (Printout is an extended text of the work published in 1998. Accompanied by editorial notes by Lillian Milgram Schapiro)
      - Worldview in painting: art and society: selected papers, volume 5. Ne York: George Braziller, 1999
        - Annotated book, 1999 (Box 277, Folder 4)
          (Annotations by Lillian Milgram Schapiro)
        - Editorial ntoes, 1999 (Box 277, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1998-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 277, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Contract, 1998 (Box 277, Folder 8)
        - Reviews, 1999 (Box 277, Folder 9)
      - The unity of Picasso's art. New York: George Braziller, 2000
        (Although published posthumously in 2000 Schapiro himself worked on the draft for this manuscript in 1985 while working with Gittelman Film Association on their video of Schapiro's lecture on Picasso for the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Portions of this manuscript incorporate Schapiro's lectures on Picasso from the following institutions: Brandeis University (1967) and the Albright-Knox Art Gallery (1973). Typescripts, research notes, and outlines can be found for these two lectures at Sub-Subseries: III.3.4: 1960s and Sub-Subseries: III.3.5: 1970s respectively)
      - Annotated typescripts, 1985-2000 (Box 278, Folder 1)
        (Accompanied by Lillian Milgram Schaipro's editorial notes)
      - Annotated typescripts, 1985-2000 (Box 278, Folder 2)
        (Typescript chiefly used to consolidate the Brandeis and Albright-Knox lectures for the video presentation)
      - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1985-2000 (Box 278, Folder 3)
      - Editorial notes, 1980s (Box 278, Folder 4)
      - Reproductions, 2000, (4 Folders) (Box 278, Folder 5 to 8)
      - Reproductions list and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 278, Folder 9)
      - Reviews, 2000 (Box 278, Folder 10)
    - Meyer Schapiro: his painting, drawing, and sculpture. New York: Harry N. Abrams, 2000
      - Preface / John Russell -- Annotated printouts and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and editorial notes, 1998-2000 (Box 279, Folder 2)
      - Reviews, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 3)
    - Language of forms: lectures on insular manuscript art / foreword by Charles E. Pierce, Jr.; introduction by Jane E. Rosenthal. New York: Pierpont Morgan Library, 2005
      (Material for this publication is derived from Schapiro's Franklin Jasper Walls lectures held at the Pierpont Morgan library. Consult Sub-Subseries: III.3.4: 1960s for materials relating to that lecture)
      - Chapter 1 -- Annotated typescripts and research notes, 1987 (Box 279, Folder 4)
        (Typescript is Schapiro's original and used as reference for the manuscript of this publication)
      - Chapter 1 -- Annotated printouts and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 5)
      - Chapter 2 -- Printouts and editorial notes, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 6)
      - Chapter 3 -- Printout, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 4 -- Printout, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 5 -- Printout, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 9)
      - Chapter 6 -- Printout, 2000 (Box 279, Folder 10)
      - Editorial notes, 1980s-2005 (Box 279, Folder 11 to 12)
      - Editorial notes, 1980s-2005 (Box 280, Folder 1)